Andre De Coppet Collection, 1566-1936 (bulk 1770-1865 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Massachusetts Towns, 1691-1875; 5 boxes (2 partial)
  - Beverly, Mass, 1690 December 25; 1 folder
    - Land Agreement, 1690 December 25; 1 item (Folder 6)
      Between brothers Thomas & Isaac Woodbury. 1 p.
  - Billerica, Mass, 1827 January 18; 1 folder
    - Letter, 1827 January 18; 1 item (Folder 7)
      ALS from Marshall Preston to John Locke. Writes about both American and English politics, specifically mentioning allied powers and British Prime Minister (George) Canning. 3 pp.
  - Boston, Mass, 1728 June 7-1831 May 2; 1 folder
    - Receipt, 1728 June 7; 1 item (Folder 8)
      Issued to William Dudley, Trustee of Roxbury, for repaying part of a loan. On a small slip of paper.
    - Bill of Exchange, 1747 March 20; 1 item (Folder 8)
      From William Shirley, Governor of Massachusetts, to Paymaster General of his Majesty's Land Forces demanding money for troops who served in an expedition against Canada under General Waldo. 2 pp.
    - Marriage Announcement, 1755 December 22; 1 item (Folder 8)
      Printed form signed by Boston Town Clerk Ezekiel Goldthwait announcing the marriage of Thomas Greenleaf and Mehetable Harris. On a small slip of paper.
    - Tax Form, 1766; 1 item (Folder 8)
      Tax assessment for William Wane, issued by collector Sampson Salter. Printed form. On a small slip of paper.
    - Committee of Donations, 1774 November 16; 1 item (Folder 8)
      DS, Boston. From the Committee of Donations of Boston to the Committee of Correspondence of Glastonbury, CT. Thanking them for their sympathy and generosity in supporting Boston. Signed by Henry Hill. With a copy of the Glastonbury Committee letter of June 23, 1774. 3 pp. total.
    - Pass, 1775 November 30; 1 item (Folder 8)
      A printed pass issued by the Boston Committee of Donations to Nathan Spear and his family of four, who are leaving the town of Boston. Recommending them to the selectmen of the towns of Massachusetts, asking for the "charity and assistance of our benevolent sympathizing brethren." Signed by Edward L. Sanders, Clerk. Half leaf.
    - Republican Institution of Boston, 1818 December 17-1831 May 2; portion of 1 folder
      The items were once owned by Republican Institution subscriber George Homer.
      - Circular Letter, 1818 December 17; 1 item (Folder 8)
        Printed letter announcing a general meeting. Signed by Secretary Thaddeus Page. 1 p.
      - Circular Letter, 1819 January 20; 1 item (Folder 8)
        Printed letter announcing an upcoming meeting for subscribers. 1 p.
      - Circular Letter, 1819 March 20; 1 item (Folder 8)
        Printed letter calling a meeting, with proposed by-laws. 3 pp.
      - Subscription, 1831 May 2; 1 item (Folder 8)
        Certifying George Homer as a subscriber to the Republican Institution. 2 pp.
  - Boxborough, Mass, 1814 February 1; 1 folder
    - Tax Form, 1814 February 1; 1 item (Folder 9)
      Printed form filled in with measurement and value of land owned by Nathan Raymond. 1 p.
  - Brookfield, Mass, 1748-1807 May 18; 1 folder
    - Promissory Note, 1748-1752; 1 item (Folder 10)
      Binding Robert Andrews to pay Jonathan French, signed 1748. In 1752, French signed the money over to Jonathan Wood (written on back). 2 pp.
    - Letter of Resignation, 1807 May 18; 1 item (Folder 10)
      From Daniel Bullard to Caleb Strong, Governor of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, resigning as Coroner of Worcester County and recommending a replacement. 1 p.
  - Brookline, Mass, 1744 September-1785 July 16; 1 folder
    - Town Ruling, 1744 September; 1 item (Folder 11)
      A 1747 copy of a 1744 Brookline town ruling vetoing a highway. 1 p.
    - Highway Rate Assessment, 1774 May 20; 1 item (Folder 11)
      List of names and amounts taxed Brookline residents for Highway Rate. Sent by town assessors to William Ackers, Surveyor of Highways. 2 pp.
    - Petition for Reimbursement, 1776 January 8; 1 item (Folder 11)
      Sent by Jonathan Harris to the Colony of Massachusetts Bay for boarding destitute widow Rebekah Vaughn of Boston. 1 p.
    - Muster Registration, 1785 July 16; 1 item (Folder 11)
      Muster-Master of Suffolk County registering Asaph Bisbee for one year service. Printed form. 1 p.
  - Chelmsford, Mass, 1764 March 30; 1 folder
    - Writ, 1764 March 30; 1 item (Folder 12)
      Ordering William Barrit to pay Zechariah Parker or contest in court. Printed form. 1 p.
  - Cohasset, Mass, 1771 June 8; 1 folder
    - Land Deed, 1771 June 8; 1 item (Folder 13)
      Deed between Robert Elmes and Benjamin Stutson for house in Cohasset. Printed form. 1 p.
  - Dedham, Mass, 1765 September 2; 1 folder
    - Court Ruling, 1765 September 2; 1 item (Folder 14)
      Ruling by Justice Abel Lawrence in case of Ephraim Ware v. Mary Patterson for nonpayment of physician's fees. 1 p.
  - Duxbury, Mass, 1804 June 22; 1 folder
    - Letter, 1804 June 22; 1 item (Folder 15)
      Printed letter decrying "venal presses" accompanied by ALS from Shilborn Whitman to George Partridge (former Massachusetts Congressional Representative) asking him to help protect the Commonwealth by battling bad press. 2 pp.
  - Falmouth, Mass, 1727 May 1; 1 folder
    - Land Deed, 1727 May 1; 1 item (Folder 16)
      Transferring land from John Lane to Joshua Woodbury. 1 p.
    - Letter of Administration, dates not examined; 1 item (Folder 16)
      Printed form letter granting John Wheelwright administrative rights over the estate of his late uncle, John Jordan. 1 p.
  - Gloucester, Mass, 1815; 1 folder
    - Tax Receipt, 1815; 1 item (Folder 17)
      Printed form filled in with Stephen Nelson Rowley's State, County & Town taxes for 1815. On a small slip of paper.
  - Groton, Mass, 1757-1856; 2 folders
    Three individuals are prominent within the Groton town file: James Brazer, John Loring, and Abel Lawrence. Due to volume, Lawrence's papers have been separated and arranged chronologically in a second folder.
    - Account Statement, 1763-1765; 1 item (Folder 18)
      List of money owed Zechariah Wethe for services rendered to Widow Hepsibah Warren. 1 p.
    - Tax Form, 1814 January 1; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Printed form filled in by James Brazer acknowledging the yearly tax on his chaise. 1 p.
    - Tax Form, 1814 January 1; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Printed form filled in by James Brazer acknowledging the yearly tax on his phaeton. 1 p.
    - List of Taxable Property, 1814 February 1; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Printed form filled in with measurements and value of land owned by James Brazer. 1 p.
    - List of Taxable Property, 1814 February 1; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Printed form filled in with measurements and value of land owned by Jonathan Loring. 1 p.
    - Tax Form, 1815 June 13; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Printed form filled in by Jonathan Loring on behalf of Ezra Farnsworth acknowledging yearly tax on Farnsworth's chaise. 1 p.
    - Tax Form, 1817 January 7; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Printed form filled in by Jonathan Loring acknowledging the yearly tax on his chaise. 1 p.
    - Tax Form, 1817 January 7; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Printed form filled in by Sampson Wood acknowledging the yearly tax on his chaise. 1 p.
    - Letter, 1826 February 11; 1 item (Folder 18)
      ALS from Bradford Russell to John Locke expressing thanks and giving news of Groton including a religious controversy and the suicide of Colonel Sampson Wood (see also: Pepperell file). 1 p.
    - Newspaper Clipping, 1855; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Two identical newspaper clippings announcing Jonathan Loring's death and bequests.
    - Letter, 1856 May 5; 1 item (Folder 18)
      ALS from Joshua Green to S(amuel) G(ardner) Drake (author of History of Boston,1852) regarding historical research. 1 p.
    - Newspaper Clipping, circa 1856; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Book review from The New York Tribune in which James Brazer of Groton is mentioned.
    - Valuation, undated; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Printed form filled in with valuation of household furniture kept by James Brazer. Probable date circa 1814. 1 p.
    - Valuation, undated; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Printed form filled in with valuation of household furniture kept by Jonathan Loring. 1 p.
    - Broadside, undated; 1 item (Folder 18)
      Printed broadside for Benjamin P. Dix's store in Groton, Mass. Crossed out type suggests it was switched from a drug store to a shoe store. 1 p.
    - Papers of Abel Lawrence (2 of 2), 1757-1770; 1 folder
      Various papers issued by and to Justice of the Peace Abel Lawrence including many writs involving various residents of Groton. Almost all the writs require one party to pay another party or contest in court. Most have notes and final judgments written on the back. All writs are half leaf printed forms with names and specifics filled in by hand.
      - Receipt and Account Statement, 1757-1758; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Issued to Lawrence by Jo. Read detailing fees, payments, and balance due for work related to court cases. 1 p.
      - Writ, 1762 August 23; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Josiah Farwell to pay Timothy Heald. 1 p.
      - Receipt, 1763; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Copy of receipt issued to Josiah Farwell. 1 p.
      - Note, 1763 April 27; 1 item (Folder 19)
        From Sarah Marteen (or Martin) to Abel Lawrence requesting a promissory note left in his care. 1 p.
      - Note, 1763 June 19; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Note signed by William Little concerning a receipt issued to Josiah Farwell. 1 p.
      - Court Bill, 1764 July; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Court bill in case of Abel Fox v. William Russell. 1 p.
      - Writ, 1764 July 7; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Isaiah Holden to pay William Wulling. 1 p.
      - Writ, 1764 August 15; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Court settlement ordering William Spaulding (or Spalding) to pay Silas Parkhunt. 1 p.
      - Writ, 1765 January 10; 1 item (Folder 19)
        John Stone to pay William Little. 1 p.
      - Writ, 1765 January 15; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Hepsibah Warren to pay Zechariah Wethe. 1 p.
      - Writ, 1765 January 18; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Oliver Farnsworth to pay William Little (copy 1 of 2). 1 p.
      - Writ, 1765 January 18; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Oliver Farnsworth to pay William Little (copy 2 of 2). 1 p.
      - Writ, 1765 February 22; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Solomon Farnsworth to pay William Little. 1 p.
      - Writ, 1766 February 17; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Court settlement ordering Shattuck Blood to pay Israel Hobart. 1 p.
      - Writ, 1766 July 12; 1 item (Folder 19)
        David Keemp (or Kemp) to pay Amos Holdin. 1 p.
      - Writ, 1768 April 4; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Abel Parker to pay Jabez Keep. 1 p.
      - Court Ruling, 1768 May 23; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Ruling in case of Farnsworth v. Trowbridge. 1 p.
      - Promissory Note, 1769 May 15; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Phineas Butler to pay John Gragg. Note reads that Lawrence gave judgment on January 15, 1770. 1 p.
      - Account Statement, 1769 November; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Statement of money owed Cotton Proctor by Isaac Nutting for fabric purchased. Note reads that Lawrence gave judgment on the account January 29, 1770. 1 p.
      - Writ, 1770 January 16; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Isaac Nutting to pay Cotton Proctor. 1 p.
      - Summons, 1770 February 10; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Addressed to six men requiring them to appear in case of Francis Mitchell v. Joseph Page. Signed on back by each of the men. 2 pp.
      - Account Statement, undated; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Account of various promissory notes issued by Lawrence. 1 p.
      - Bill, undated; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Bill from Thad. Mason to Captain Abel Lawrence. 1 p.
      - Account Statement, undated; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Settling accounts between Abel Lawrence and Thomas Little. 1 p.
      - Account Statement, undated; 1 item (Folder 19)
        Statement of money owed Lawrence by Peter Wright. 1 p.
  - Hadley, Mass, 1786 October 20; 1 folder
    - Receipt, 1786 October 20; 1 item (Folder 20)
      Receipt from Nathaniel Appleton "Continental Loan Officer, in the State of Massachusetts" given to Oliver Smith of Hadley. Printed form. 1 p.
  - Haverhill, Mass, 1772 October 25; 1 folder
    - Log entry (copy), 1772 October 25; 1 item (Folder 21)
      Copy of entry written by Edw. Barnard, pastor of First Church in Haverhill, recording church's vote to dismiss and recommend Jonathan & Elizabeth Sawyer to a new church in Atkinson. 1 p.
  - Hingham, Mass, 1759 June 29-1784 March 15; 1 folder
    - Promissory Note, 1759 June 29; 1 item (Folder 22)
      Binding Robt. Garnett to pay Peter Tour. 1 p.
    - Log entry (copy), 1784 March 15; 1 item (Folder 22)
      Copy of entry from Hingham town records describing the land owned by the late John Thaxter. Attested by Town Clerk Benjamin Cushing. 1 p.
  - Holliston, Mass, 1775 February; 1 folder
    - Letter, 1775 February; 1 item (Folder 23)
      ALS from John Stone to Mr. Fleet, requesting he publish a rebuttal to a false and scurrilous piece written by Ephraim Littlefield. 2 pp.
  - Ipswich, Mass, 1754 July 22-1813 January 29; 1 folder
    - Letter of Administration, 1754 July 22; 1 item (Folder 24)
      Printed form letter filled out by Thomas Berry, Judge of the Probate of Wills, granting Sarah Fuller administrative rights over the estate of her late husband, William Fuller. 1 p.
    - Letter, 1813 January 29; 1 item (Folder 24)
      Unfinished letter regarding a Mr. Norris and a new edition of tunes. Writer and recipient not specified in author's hand, but penciled note reads "Joseph Dana, Ipswich." 2 pp.
    - Broadside, undated; 1 item (Folder 24)
      Order of Exercises at the Ipswich Washingtonian Celebration. Includes lyrics to an original temperance hymn. Printed by S.N. Dickinson, Boston. 1 p.
  - Leicester, Mass, 1763 December 20-1789 October 14; portions of 2 boxes
    - Tax Return, 1763 December 20; 1 item (Folder 25)
      Sent by Assessors of Leicester to Harrison Gray, Province Treasurer, giving account of taxes levied. 1 p.
    - Clipping, undated; 1 item (Folder 25)
      Clipping of death notice of Thomas & Samuel Denny, two of the Leicester town assessors (see above item).
    - Letter (copy), 1782 October 17; 1 item (Folder 25)
      Copy of letter sent to Selectmen of the towns of Leicester and Sheffield regarding which town should count Aaron Root, Jr., a recently returned Continental soldier, in its quota. 1 p.
    - Commission, 1789 October 14; 1 item
      Issued by the Commonwealth of Massachusetts commissioning William Henshaw as a Justice of the Peace for Worcester County. Printed form. Signed by John Avery, Jr., Secretary, and John Hancock, Governor. On back is handwritten acknowledgement that Henshaw appeared before Lieutenant Governor S(amuel) Adams. 1 p.
  - Leominster, Mass, 1832 May 7; 1 folder
    - Letter, 1832 May 7; 1 item (Folder 26)
      ALS from Thomas Jackson to Samuel A. Allen, Public Store Keeper, requesting the bearer of the letter be entrusted with a box addressed to Jackson. 1 p.
  - Littleton, Mass, 1755 April-1770 June 4; 1 folder
    File contains writs and judgments issued by Justice of the Peace Abel Lawrence involving various residents of Littleton, notably the Russell and Fox families. Each writ requires one party to pay another party as a result of a court settlement. Recipients acknowledged payment on back. All writs are half leaf printed forms with names and specifics filled in by hand.
    - Receipt, 1755 April; 1 item (Folder 27)
      Signed by Nathanial Russell acknowledging money received from James Stevens via Justice Abel Lawrence. 1 p.
    - Promissory Note, 1763 October 6; 1 item (Folder 27)
      Solomon Farnsworth to pay Benjamin Hutchins. Note reads that Lawrence gave judgment on March 11, 1765. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1764 August 18; 1 item (Folder 27)
      William Russell to pay Nathan Proctor. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1764 October 15; 1 item (Folder 27)
      William Russell to pay Sarah Fox. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1764 October 15; 1 item (Folder 27)
    - Writ, 1764 October 17; 1 item (Folder 27)
    - Writ, 1764 October 17; 1 item (Folder 27)
    - Writ, 1764 October 25; 1 item (Folder 27)
    - Writ, 1764 November 1; 1 item (Folder 27)
      William Russell to pay Samuel Preston. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1765 January 16; 1 item (Folder 27)
      Isaac Russell to pay William Russell. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1765 February 25; 1 item (Folder 27)
      Ephraim Corey to pay William Russell. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1765 May 1; 1 item (Folder 27)
      William Russell to pay Timothy Fox. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1765 May 1; 1 item (Folder 27)
    - Writ, 1765 December 7; 1 item (Folder 27)
      Isaac Russell to pay Oliver Prescott. 1 p.
    - Promissory Note, 1767 October 8; 1 item (Folder 27)
      Samuel Russell to pay Peter Fox. Note reads that Lawrence gave judgment on June 27, 1768. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1770 June 4; 1 item (Folder 27)
      Oliver Hartwell to pay James Reed. 1 p.
  - Lunenburg, Mass, 1761 March 2; 1 folder
    - Writ, 1761 March 2; 1 item (Folder 28)
      Ordering Thad. Mason to pay Pearson Eaton or contest in court. Issued by Abel Lawrence. Printed form. 1 p.
  - Lynn, Mass, 1823 January 21-1861 March 11; 1 folder
    - Letter, 1823 January 21; 1 item (Folder 29)
      ALS from Otis Rockwood, Pastor of First Congregational Church of Christ in Lynn, Mass., recommending George Martin to a new congregation. 1 p.
    - Receipt, 1847 November 18; 1 item (Folder 29)
      Receipt for George Martin's payment of his daughter's tuition. Signed Jacob Batchelder. 1 p.
    - Letter, 1850 October 22; 1 item (Folder 29)
      ALS from J.C. Stickney, on behalf of the Key Stone Club of Lynn, inviting the Boston branch of the club to a Democratic Demonstration. 1 p.
    - Letter, 1858 August 3; 1 item (Folder 29)
      Reverend in Lynn, MA. ALS from P. Cooke to Reverend Dr. Felt about subscribers to a Review and an upcoming meeting. 1 p.
    - Poem, 1861 March 11; 1 item (Folder 29)
      Handwritten poem entitled "But." Penciled on back is note that was written by Warren Newhall and read at the Alliance Club. 2 pp.
  - Marblehead, Mass, 1774 August 16; 1 folder
    - Call to Meeting, 1774 August 16; 1 item (Folder 30)
      Official communication between the towns of Marblehead and Newbury Port planning a meeting to protest the enactment of "oppressive acts" by Parliament. Signed Benjamin Boden, Town Clerk of Marblehead and John Gerry, Clerk of Newbury Port. 2 pp.
  - Methuen, Mass, 1771 May 14; 1 folder
    - Approbation Letter, 1771 May 14; 1 item (Folder 31)
      ALS signed by ministers William Balch, Abner Bayley, and Samuel Williams approving and recommending Stephen Peabody as an occasional preacher. 1 p.
  - Milton, Mass, dates not examined; 1 item
  - Deed, 1715 April 8; 1 item
    Deed of Joseph Billing of Milton, relinquishing rights to his father's estate. 1 p.
    - Receipt, 1791 October 26; 1 item (Folder 32)
      Receipt from Nathaniel Appleton, Commissioner of Loans for State of Massachusetts, given to Abel Alleyne. Printed form. 1 p.
  - Nantucket, Mass, 1817 April 2; 1 folder
    - Letter, 1817 April 2; 1 item (Folder 33)
      ALS from William Garritt to Benjamin Austin (Commissioner of Loans for Boston) requesting Austin forward an affidavit to Washington. 1 p.
  - Newburyport, Mass, 1774-1788 May 21; 1 folder
    - Petition for Reimbursement, 1774; 1 item (Folder 34)
      Issued by Judith Bradbury to the Province of Massachusetts Bay for boarding William Tumey in the weeks before his death. 1 p.
    - Letter, 1788 May 21; 1 item (Folder 34)
      ALS from Dan Killam to Doctor W. Stearns. Letter originally sent with twelve pounds spirit of vitriol. 1 p.
  - Newton, Mass, 1814 June 28; 1 folder
    - Pew Certificates, 1814 June 28; 1 item (Folder 35)
      Two pew certificates issued by Solomon Curtis and Thomas Durant, Wardens of St. Mary's Chapel in Newton, to Simon Elliot for purchase of pews 22 and 46. 1 p. each.
  - Pepperell, Mass, 1753 March-1826 February 11; 1 folder
    - Bill, 1753 March; 1 item (Folder 36)
      From Jonathan Woods to David Shattuck for carpentry work. 1 p.
    - Bill, 1754 December; 1 item (Folder 36)
      From Jonathan Woods to Thomas Seward for making clothes. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1765 July 2; 1 item (Folder 36)
      Ordering Nathanial Sartell to pay William Spaulding (or Spalding) or contest in court. Constable's notes and ruling of Justice Abel Lawrence written on back. Printed form. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1766 August 29; 1 item (Folder 36)
      Ordering Charles Wetherell to pay William Little or contest in court. Constable's notes and ruling of Justice Abel Lawrence written on back. Printed form. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1766 December 19; 1 item (Folder 36)
      Ordering William Warran to pay Ebenezer Champney or contest in court. Constable's notes and ruling of Justice Abel Lawrence written on back. Printed form. 1 p.
    - Bill, 1770 January; 1 item (Folder 36)
      From James Robinson to Parker Emerson charging for carpentry work and worsted stockings (see accompanying writ below). 1 p.
    - Writ, 1770 February 1; 1 item (Folder 36)
      Ordering Parker Emerson to pay James Robinson or contest in court. Constable's notes and ruling of Justice Abel Lawrence written on back. Printed form. 1 p.
    - Writ, 1770 February 1; 1 item (Folder 36)
      Ordering Samuel Hall to pay James Robinson or contest in court. Contested bill attached. Constable's notes and ruling of Justice Abel Lawrence written on back. Printed form. 3 pp.
    - Letter, 1778 February 10; 1 item (Folder 36)
      ALS from Selectmen of Pepperell to Samuel Philips (founder of Phillips Academy, Andover) requesting a refund for purchased gunpowder that was not fit for use. 1 p.
    - Letter, 1826 February 11; 1 item (Folder 36)
      ALS from James Lewis to John Locke concerned over complaints about the local post office. Also mentions recent suicide of Colonel Sampson Wood (see also: Groton). 1 p.
  - Roxbury, Mass, 1757 March 18; 1 folder
    - Note, 1757 March 18; 1 item (Folder 37)
      Note promising payment to Peter Hammond upon his passing muster and being accepted for an enlisted man in the second foot company of militia in Roxbury. Signed by Jos. Dudley and Joseph Mayo. 1 p.
  - Salem, Mass, 1787 July 16-1831 September 29; 1 folder
    - Letter, 1787 July 16; 1 item (Folder 38)
      ALS from J. Waldo to Dr. William Stearns apologizing for late payment. 1 p.
    - Letter, 1790 May 11; 1 item (Folder 38)
      ALS from Gabriel Holman to Joseph Sprague. Writes of the availability of molasses and a prolonged trip to the Caribbean. 1 p.
    - Receipt, 1790 November 23; 1 item (Folder 38)
      Issued by B. Herbert Hathorne, on behalf of his father Jon Hathorne, to William Stearns for purchase of allspice. 1 p.
    - Bill, 1790 December 4; 1 item (Folder 38)
      From Daniel Hathorne to William Harns. 1 p.
    - Receipt, 1793 February 23; 1 item (Folder 38)
      Issued by Enos Briggs to Elias H(asket) Derby (prominent New England merchant) for settling account balance. Later note on back gives brief history of Briggs. 1 p.
    - Bill, 1800; 1 item (Folder 38)
      From John Hathorne to William Stearns for velvet cape. 1 p.
    - Deed, 1812 March 27; 1 item (Folder 38)
      Part of a deed signed by Charles & Mehetable Cleveland and Justice Amos Choate. 1 p. (torn).
    - Bill, 1815-1816; 1 item (Folder 38)
      From William Hathorne to William Stearns for a paint brush and fabric. 1 p.
    - Invoice of Cargo, 1831 September 29; 1 item (Folder 38)
      Invoice of cargo on board brig Neptune, Salem. Bound for India under master William Osgood. With the names and shares of her owners. 2 pp.
  - Scituate, Mass, 1716 May 25-1817 January 21; 2 folders